<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-11T02:33:19+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jinho’s Tech Blog</title><subtitle>개발에 대한 이야기를 담아내다</subtitle><author><name>Jinho</name></author><entry><title type="html">최신 게시글</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/man-must-explore.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="최신 게시글" /><published>2020-01-31T23:45:13+09:00</published><updated>2020-01-31T23:45:13+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/man-must-explore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/31/man-must-explore.html"><![CDATA[<p>Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</p>

<p>Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.</p>

<p>What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.</p>

<p>A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.</p>

<p>For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">The Final Frontier</h2>

<p>There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.</p>

<p>There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.</p>

<blockquote class="blockquote">The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.</blockquote>

<p>Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">Reaching for the Stars</h2>

<p>As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450" alt="Demo Image">
<span class="caption text-muted">To go places and do things that have never been done before – that’s what living is all about.</span>

<p>Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.</p>

<p>As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.</p>

<p>Placeholder text by <a href="http://spaceipsum.com/">Space Ipsum</a>. Photographs by <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jinho</name></author><category term="test" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">에라 모르겠다.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/27/dinosaurs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="에라 모르겠다." /><published>2020-01-27T12:45:13+09:00</published><updated>2020-01-27T12:45:13+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/27/dinosaurs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/27/dinosaurs.html"><![CDATA[<p>코딩의 세계는 끝없는 탐험의 연속입니다. 새로운 기술과 방법론이 계속해서 등장하고, 우리는 그것들을 배우고 적용하며 성장합니다. 개발자로서의 여정은 마치 우주 탐험과도 같죠. 끝없는 가능성이 펼쳐져 있고, 매 순간이 새로운 도전입니다.</p>

<p>처음 프로그래밍을 시작했을 때를 떠올려봅니다. 'Hello World'를 출력하는 것만으로도 가슴이 두근거렸던 그 순간, 지금도 생생합니다. 그때의 설렘과 호기심은 지금도 제 안에 그대로 남아있습니다.</p>

<p>버그를 해결할 때면 마치 추리 소설의 탐정이 된 것 같은 기분이 듭니다. 로그를 분석하고, 코드를 한 줄 한 줄 따라가며 문제의 원인을 찾아내는 과정은 때로는 힘들지만, 그만큼 해결했을 때의 기쁨도 큽니다.</p>

<h2 class="section-heading">끊임없는 도전</h2>

<p>개발자의 길을 걷기로 결심한 순간부터, 매일이 새로운 배움의 연속입니다. 새로운 프레임워크가 등장하고, 새로운 패러다임이 제시되며, 우리는 계속해서 변화하고 적응해야 합니다. 하지만 이런 변화야말로 이 직업의 매력이 아닐까요?</p>

<blockquote class="blockquote">어제의 코드를 보며 부끄러워할 수 있다는 것은 그만큼 우리가 성장했다는 증거입니다. 완벽한 코드는 없습니다. 다만 더 나은 코드를 위해 노력하는 과정이 있을 뿐입니다.</blockquote>

<h2 class="section-heading">함께 만드는 미래</h2>

<p>오픈소스 커뮤니티의 힘은 놀랍습니다. 전 세계의 개발자들이 서로의 지식을 공유하고, 함께 문제를 해결해나가는 모습은 정말 인상적입니다. 많은 도움을 받았던 것처럼, 저도 언젠가는 다른 개발자들에게 도움이 되는 존재가 되고 싶습니다.</p>

<p>개발은 결코 혼자 하는 일이 아닙니다. 동료들과 함께 고민하고, 해결책을 찾아가는 과정에서 우리는 더 나은 개발자로 성장합니다. 때로는 격렬한 토론도 필요하고, 의견 충돌도 있겠지만, 그 과정이 우리를 더 단단하게 만듭니다.</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="https://source.unsplash.com/Mn9Fa_wQH-M/800x450" alt="코딩 이미지">
<span class="caption text-muted">새로운 가능성을 향해 도전하는 것, 그것이 바로 개발자의 삶입니다.</span>

<p>기술은 계속해서 발전할 것이고, 우리는 그 속도를 따라가야 합니다. 하지만 잊지 말아야 할 것은 기술의 본질입니다. 우리가 만드는 것은 단순한 코드가 아닌, 사람들의 삶을 더 나은 방향으로 변화시킬 수 있는 솔루션이라는 것을.</p>

<p>이 글은 <a href="#">개발자의 일상</a>을 담았습니다. 사진 출처: <a href="https://unsplash.com/">Unsplash</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Jinho</name></author><category term="New" /><category term="tag2" /><category term="tag3" /><category term="tag4" /><category term="tag5" /><category term="tag6" /><category term="tag" /><category term="tag212" /><category term="tag33" /><category term="tag211" /><category term="tag2111" /><category term="tag212312312123" /><category term="tag2123132" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[코딩의 세계는 끝없는 탐험의 연속입니다. 새로운 기술과 방법론이 계속해서 등장하고, 우리는 그것들을 배우고 적용하며 성장합니다. 개발자로서의 여정은 마치 우주 탐험과도 같죠. 끝없는 가능성이 펼쳐져 있고, 매 순간이 새로운 도전입니다.]]></summary></entry></feed>